Marcelo Boeira

Berlin, Germany +49 176 65355475 me@marceloboeira.com https://marceloboeira.com

Summary

Agnostic Lead Engineer with 9+ years of experience working on large-scale web applications.

Currently, supporting businesses to scale their platforms by building and leading great teams, reliable and high-available architecture, hiring, culture and career growth.

Passionate about software that makes an impact, culture, high-availability, and open source.

Education

Electrical Engineering, University of the Sinos Valley

São Leopoldo, Brazil

Professional Experiences

Engineering Lead, Hotel Partnerships, Airbnb

Berlin, Germany — 03/2019 - Currently

Lead Site Reliability Engineer, heycar (Volkswagen & Daimler Venture)

Berlin, Germany — 10/2017 - 03/2019

Lead Software Engineer, Pricing, Movinga GmbH

Berlin, Germany — 10/2016 - 11/2017

Software Engineer, Globo.com

Porto Alegre, Brazil — 06/2015 - 09/2016

Software Developer (Remote), PrimeSystems

Porto Alegre, Brazil — 06/2014 - 06/2015

Technical Writer / Content Creator, iMasters

São Paulo, Brazil — 2012 - 2015

Lead Developer, Nucleo Sistemas

Caxias do Sul, Brazil — 04/2012 - 06/2014

Junior Software 'Developer, Nucleo Sistemas

Caxias do Sul, Brazil — 09/2011 - 04/2012